TWUA Photographs 6924 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
TWUA Photographs
1940-1970
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
6924 P
0.44 cubic feet
0.4 linear ft.
Gelatin silver print, photographs.
Photographs of strikes, union events, and portraits of union officials.
10066254
Scope and Contents
Includes photographs of strikes at Boott Mills and Wood Mills. Photographs of union events such as parades, election participation, and conventions. Also includes photographs of a ITGWF (International Textile and Garment Workers Federation) meeting. Also portraits of union officials.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6924 G: TWUA Graphics 6924: TWUA Records
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives 227 Ives Hall Tower Road Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheelref@cornell.edu https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/
Compiled by:
R. Miles, October 16, 2017
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, December 12, 2017
Elections; Labor union locals; Labor union meetings; Labor union members; Labor unions; Labor; Management; Parties; Raffles; Recreation; Strikes and lockouts; Textile industry; Textile Workers' Strike, Lowell, Mass., 1947-1948; Textile workers; Lawrence (Mass.); Lowell (Mass.); Ax, Joel; Bachrach, Fabian; Banks, Clarence M.; Belanger, J. William; Boisclair, Gerard; Buckley, John J.; Canzano, Victor J.; Chupka, John.; Clark, Charles; Couture, Jean Marc; Daoust, J. Harold.; Demers, Bert; Doolan, Edward F.; DuChessi, William; Dyson, Alford; Easto, Clare; Hodgman, Alton; Kislowski, Stan; Laliberte, Euclide; Lane, Thomas Joseph,; Mello, Joseph S.; Oliver, Ronald; Pollock, William.; Rantane, Bruno.; Renaud, Alain; Stetin, Sol, 1910-2005; Swaity, Paul; Viveiros, Joseph; Viveiros, John; Watson, George; Boott Mills (Lowell, Mass.); Congress of Industrial Organizations (U.S.); Merrimack Manufacturing Company; Textile Workers Union of America; Wood Worsted Mill (Lawrence, Mass.)
10066254
- Photographs of strikes and union events (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Textile workers on picket line at Boott Mills, Lowell, Mass., black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Gelatin silver print, 1947-1948. Image depicts Boott Mill workers on a picket line in Lowell, Mass., probably during the 1947-1948 strike. Both men and women are represented in the picketing. Sign on left reads: "Boott Mills Local 538 On Strike" and sign held by picketer on the far right reads: "No Contract No Work." Sign held by woman picketer at the front of the line probably says No Contract No Work. See item 2 in this folder for a very similar. 25.25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 2: Close-up of textile workers on picket line at Boott Mills, Lowell, Mass., black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, 1947-1948. Image depicts Boott Mill workers on a picket line in Lowell, Mass., probably during the 1947-1948 strike. Both men and women are represented in the picketing. One sign reads: "Boott Mills Local 538 On Strike." Three others read: "We have been Marching [ ] Weeks Respect our picket line." Others are too blurry to make out. See item 1 in this folder for a very similar view. 25.25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 3: Textile workers on picket line in front of Wood Mill (American Woolen Company), Lawrence, Mass., black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, ca. 1950. Image depicts textile workers on a picket line in front of the Wood Mill (part of the American Woolen Company) in Lawrence, Mass., probably ca. 1950. Local 227 T.W.U.A.-C.I.O. is represented by a sign at the head of the line. Picketers are both male and female. Probably in late winter; picketers are wearing heavy overcoats. See items 4 and 5 in this folder for other views of picketers during this strike. 25.75 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 4: Picket line circling in front of Wood Mill (American Woolen Company), Lawrence, Mass., black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, ca. 1950. Image depicts textile workers on a picket line circling in front of the Wood Mill (part of the American Woolen Company) in Lawrence, Mass., probably ca. 1950. Sign held by picketer in foreground reads: "We Want Guarantees Against High Living Costs." Sign held by picketer in background reads: "No Workload Increase Without A Voice!" Both men and women are on the picket line, although this view shows primarily men. Probably in late winter; picketers are wearing heavy overcoats. See items 3 and 5 in this folder for other views of picketers during this strike. 25.75 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 5: Female workers on picket line in front of Wood Mill (American Woolen Company), Lawrence, Mass., black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, ca. 1950. Image depicts textile workers on a picket line in front of the Wood Mill (part of the American Woolen Company) in Lawrence, Mass., probably ca. 1950. There are a few men in the background but the group is primarily female. Although none are holding picket signs, this photo was taken in the same location as item 3 in this folder. Probably in late winter; picketers are wearing heavy overcoats. See items 3 and 4 in this folder for other views of picketers during this strike. 25.5 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 8: TWUA parade float, Lawrence (Mass.) Centennial celebration, 1953; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, June 7-14, 1953. Image depicts a TWUA parade float in a parade during the Lawrence, Mass., Centennial celebration, held between June 7 and June 14, 1953. Float is designed to resemble bolts of cloth stacked on top of one another. Onlookers line the parade route in the background. 25.5 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 9: TWUA national convention delegate winners and losers, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, 1950-1955? Image depicts a man pushing a wheelbarrow (the loser) with another man in the wheelbarrow (the winner). The man pushing the wheelbarrow wears a sign "I Lost" while the man in the wheelbarrow holds a sign "Local 227 T.W.U.A.-C.I.O. Good Luck National Convention Delegates." Another man holidng a lunchbag stands to the side. Location unknown; photo taken outside on street; cafe sign in background. 20.5 x 25.5 cm.
  - Item 10: Women in voting booths at TWUA election?, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, 1948-1950? Image depicts two women posing in an election booth, while another woman is seen in an election booth with her back to the camera. A young man gestures towards the camera, while another man is walking away on the side. Probably a TWUA election, but location is unknown. 25.5 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 11: Election supporter and voter, Lowell, Mass., black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, 1948-1950? Image depicts a woman handing out a pamphlet or leaflet to a man outside what may be a voting place. The woman stands in front of a sign reading "Ward 8 Precinct 3"; another sign on the board reads "City of Lowell Polling Places." It is unclear what election this is or what the connection is to the TWUA, although she is presumably supporting a candidate favorable to unions. 25.5 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 12: Local 227 TWUA-CIO election, unknown location, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, 1945-1950? Image depicts a group of men (and one woman) standing outside what appears to be an armory building in an unknown location. One man holds a sign reading "Elect John Garafolo President Local 227 TWUA-CIO." Election taking place in December; snow piled on the ground and an advertisement outside the armory is for a Christmas concert by the U.S. Army and U.S. Air Force bands. See item 13 and 14 in this folder for another view of this image. 24.75 x 19.5 cm.
  - Item 13: Local 227 TWUA-CIO election, unknown location, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, 1945-1950? Image depicts a group of men and a few women standing outside what appears to be an armory building in an unknown location. Several of the men hold leaflets or pamphlets in their hands; one woman standing on the steps holds a sign reading "Elect John Garafolo President Local 227 TWUA-CIO." Election taking place in December; snow piled on the ground and an advertisement outside the armory is for a Christmas concert by the U.S. Army and U.S. Air Force bands. See item 12 and 14 in this folder for another view of this image. 24.75 x 19.75 cm.
  - Item 14: Group of men and women posed outside building, unknown location, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, 1946-1949? Image depicts a group of six men andtwo women posed outside a building in an unknown location. A number of suitcases sit on the sidewalk in front of them. Possibly these are delegates to the TWUA national convention? See item 12 and 13 in this folder for another view of this image. 23 x 18 cm.
  - Item 15: Raffle taking place at TWUA local?, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, 1945-1950? Image depicts a large group of people in a meeting hall as a raffle takes place at the front of the hall. Raffle prizes are on tables in the front, including bottles of liquor, toys, and other items. Audience is mostly men and women but a few children can be seen. Probably a New England local of the TWUA, but location is unknown. 25 x 17 cm.
  - Item 16: Regional union meeting of TWUA?, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, ca. 1950. Image depicts a gym filled with people, listening to some speak from a podium in the foreground (speaker's back is to the camera). People also in balcony in background. Possibly a regional union meeting of the TWUA? Location unknown. Audience consists of men and women. Photo is blurry. 25.5 x 20.75 cm.
  - Item 17: Christmas party for New England local (?) of TWUA, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, ca. 1950. Image depicts men, women and children enjoying a Christmas party, probably that of a New England local of TWUA. Christmas tree partly visible on right. A number of children seated in the foreground, some enjoying food and/or something to drink. 25.75 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 18: Group of children in park holding C.I.O. T.W.U.A. paddles, 1950; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print. Image depicts a group of children posed in a park holding paddles, all of which say C.I.O. T.W.U.A. 1939-1950. Possibly a union picnic? Paddles appear to be hand decorated, not professionally produced. Children range in age from about 4 to about 11 and include both boys and girls. Location unknown. 25.75 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 19: TWUA members (?) at party, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, ca. 1950. Image depicts a group of men and women, presumably TWUA members, possibly of the New England local, grouped around a piano, which is being played by a man with his back to the camera. Location and occasion are unknown. 25.5 x 20.75 cm.
  - Item 20: TWUA members (?) at party, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, ca. 1950. Image depicts TWUA members (?), possibly of the New England local, at a banquet of some sort. Men and women are seated at long tables in what appears to be a mill-like interior. Tables are loaded with plates of food and glasses; waitresses move along the aisles. Location and occasion are unknown; see items 21 and 22 in this folder for more views of this party. 25.25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 21: TWUA members (?) at party, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, ca. 1950. Image depicts TWUA members (?), possibly of the New England local, at a banquet of some sort. Men and women are seated at long tables in what appears to be a mill-like interior. Tables are loaded with plates of food and glasses; waitresses move along the aisles. Location and occasion are unknown; see items 20 and 22 in this folder for more views of this party. 25.25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 22: TWUA members (?) at party, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, ca. 1950. Image depicts TWUA members (?), possibly of the New England local, at a banquet of some sort. Men and women are seated at long tables in what appears to be a mill-like interior. Tables are loaded with plates of food and glasses. Location and occasion are unknown; see items 20 and 21 in this folder for more views of this party. 25.25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 23: William Pollock, Secretary-Treasurer of TWUA, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, 1950-1955. Image depicts Pollock (1899-1982) speaking in front of a microphone at an unknown dinner or meeting, probably in Lawrence, Mass., or the Lawrence area. Pollock wears three-piece suit; another man and woman are seated at the table the right of Pollock. Banner on the wall behind the table reads: "Local 615 David Brown Co."; the David Brown Co. was located in Lawrence, Mass. Written on reverse of photo: "William Pollock Sec't-Treas." which would place it before 1956, as he assumed the presidency of the TWUA in 1956. 20.25 x 25.25 cm.
  - Item 24: Minstrel show, TWUA members, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, ca. 1950. Image depicts five men sitting on a stage, dresssed in suits but wearing wigs or caps. Unknown location or occasion, but written on reverse of photo: "Minstrel show." Presumably some informal show put on by or involving TWUA members. 25.5 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 25: Sol Stetin and J. Harold Daoust, TWUA, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, 1969?. Image depicts Sol Stetin on the left, TWUA Secretary-Treasurer, and J. Harold Daoust on the right, New England director of TWUA. Glimpse of Christmas tree on right; possibly taken at New England staff conference, Dec. 10-11, 1969; see items 26, 27, and 28 in this folder. 25.25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 26: TWUA New England staff conference, 1969; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, Dec. 10-11, 1969. Image depicts TWUA officers at a New England staff conference, held at the Motel 128 in Dedham, Mass., on December 10-11, 1969. From left to right: J. Harold Daoust, Vice President and New England Regional Director; William Pollock (at the podium), General President; Paul Swaity, Director of Organization; and Joel Ax, Legal Dept. See also items 25, 27, and 28 in this folder. 25.25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 27: New England staff of TWUA honors two newly retired staffers, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, [1969?]. Image depicts several current and ex-TWUA New England staffers posed together at a banquet table; possibly taken at New England staff conference, Dec. 10-11, 1969. Left to right: George Pierce, previously retired; Frank Chupka, newly retired; Michael J. Schoonjans, previously retired; Sol Stetin, TWUA Secretary-Treasurer; J. Harold Daoust, New England Regional Director; and Gus Simas, newly retired. See also items 25, 26, and 28 in this folder. 25.25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 28: TWUA New England staff conference, 1969; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, Dec. 10-11, 1969. Image depicts TWUA officers at a New England staff conference, held at the Motel 128 in Dedham, Mass., on December 10-11, 1969. From left to right: President William Pollock; J. Harold Daoust (at the podium), Vice President and New England Regional Director; Paul Swaity, Director of Organization; and Joel Ax, Legal Dept. See also items 25, 26, and 27 in this folder. 25.25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 29: Unknown man and woman at TWUA meeting?, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, 1944-1948. Image depicts an unknown woman and man, presumably TWUA members, but the location and occasion of this photograph are unknown. 20.25 x 25 cm.
  - Item 30: Greater Fall River (Mass.) joint board installation, TWUA, 1965; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Torchia, Fall River, [photographer]. Gelatin silver print, March 27, 1965. Image depicts a group of men posed together at a joint board installation of TWUA local members (?) in Fall River, Mass., taken March 27, 1965. Front row, left to right: Alford Dyson, Business Agent; Joseph Viveiros, President; Joseph S. Mello, Secretary; Clarence M. Banks, Business Agent. Back row, left to right: J. Harold Daoust, New England Director, TWUA; Victor J. Canzano, Cotton-Rayon Director; Edward F. Doolan, Manager; Ronald Oliver, Warden; John Viveiros, Vice President. 25.5 x 20.75 cm.
  - Item 35: TWUA/New England local dinner, 1970; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print. Image depicts seven men seated at a banquet table on an unknown occasion. J. Harold Daoust, New England director for TWUA, is the second man from the right. Other men are unknown. Clipped to photo is notice dated January 8, 1970 from the desk of Joseph Salerno. 25.5 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 36: J. Harold Daoust and Bert Demers, 1969; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, June 2, 1969. Seated at a table. Montreal, Canada. 25.5 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 37: Shaking hands with pro-Mayor of Montreal, 1969; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Alain Renaud Photographe. Gelatin silver print, June 2, 1969. Left to right: J. Harold Daoust, Sol Stetin, Euclide Laliberte (pro-Mayor). Montreal, Canada. 25.5 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 38: Ten men standing behind the rostrum in the Montreal city hall, 1969; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Alain Renaud Photographe. Gelatin silver print, June 2, 1969. First row: Euclide Laliberte, Sol Stetin, George Watson, Bert Demers. Second row: Jean Marc Couture, Gerard Boisclair, Paul Swaity, Charles Clark, J. Harold Daoust, Clare Easto. 17.5 x 25.5 cm.
  - Item 39: Eleven men sitting around a conference table., black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, 1969? 25.5 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 42: Three men outside of a building, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print. Union officials at ITGWF (International Textile and Garment Workers Federation) meeting, a global textile union N.d. See items 43 and 44 for these men inside in front of a multi-lingual sign. 25.5 x 17.5 cm.
  - Item 43: Solidarity - our strength, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print. Union officials at ITGWF (International Textile and Garment Workers Federation) meeting, a global textile union N.d. Three men in front of a multi-lingual sign. See item 42 in this folder for a view of these men outside. See item 44 in this folder for a closer view of them in front of the sign. 18 x 12.5 cm.
  - Item 44: Solidarity - our strength, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print. Union officials at ITGWF (International Textile and Garment Workers Federation) meeting, a global textile union N.d. Three men in front of a multi-lingual sign. See item 42 in this folder for a view of these men outside. See item 43 in this folder for another view of them in front of the sign. 18 x 12.5 cm.
  - Item 45: Inside the conference hall, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print. Union officials at ITGWF (International Textile and Garment Workers Federation) meeting, a global textile union N.d. Six men and one woman in the foreground. Many men and women in the background. See item 46 in this folder for another view inside the conference hall. 18 x 12.5 cm.
  - Item 46: Inside the conference hall, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print. Union officials at ITGWF (International Textile and Garment Workers Federation) meeting, a global textile union N.d. Two men and one woman in the foreground. Many men and women in the background. See item 45 in this folder for another view inside the conference hall. 18 x 12.5 cm.
- Oversize strike, portrait, and other photographs, black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Item 6: Textile workers and police outside Merrimack Manufacturing Company, Lowell, Mass., during strike, black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, ca. 1950. Image depicts police lined up outside entrance to Merrimack Manufacturing Company in Lowell, Mass., during a strike around 1950. The police appear to be keeping the strikers away from a path into the company, which would be used by workers who were not striking; see item 7 in this folder. 35.5 x 28 cm.
  - Item 7: Police keep textile workers and strikers separated outside Merrimack Manufacturing Company, Lowell, Mass., during strike, black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print, ca. 1950. Image depicts police lined up outside entrance to Merrimack Manufacturing Company in Lowell, Mass., during a strike around 1950. The police appear to be keeping a path open for textile workers who were not adhering to the strike; some strikers on the left can be seen yelling; another points from the right. A man stands in the doorway of the Merrimack Woolen Mill on the left photographing the scene. See also item 6 in this folder. 35.5 x 28 cm.
  - Item 31: Joint installation party of TWUA members, 1963; black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Photo by Stan Kislowski. Gelatin silver print, Feb. 9, 1963. Image depicts six men at a joint installation party of TWUA members. Left to right: J. William Belanger; John J. Buckley (misidentified on the photo's reverse as mayor of Lawrence, Mass.--in 1963 he was a member of the Massachusetts Governor's Council); Congressman Thomas J. Lane (Lane had actually left office in January 1963 after losing re-election in 1962); TWUA Gen. Pres. William Pollock; William DuChessi; Jr. Bd. Director Alton Hodgman. Congressman Lane and TWUA Pres. Pollock are shaking hands. Possibly taken in Lawrence, Mass., as both Buckley and Lane were from Lawrence. 35.5 x 28 cm.
  - Item 32: Testimonial dinner to Bruno Rantane by Local 140 C.I.O., Maynard, Mass., 1941; black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Ashmont Photo, Boston, photographer. Gelatin silver print, Jan. 24, 1941. Image depicts men and a few women seated at banquet tables at the testimonial dinner for Bruno Rantane, given by Local 140 C.I.O. in Maynard, Mass., on Jan. 24, 1941. Long table at rear of room has men standing behind it, one of whom is presumably Rantane. 51.5 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 33: William Pollock (1899-1982), TWUA., black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Fabian Bachrach [photographer]. Gelatin silver print, 1940? Image depicts Pollock wearing three-piece suit, sitting on edge of table; photo taken in studio setting. Pollock was general president of the TWUA from 1956 to 1972, but this photograph is clearly taken earlier than his presidency. See item 41 in this folder for a photograph of Pollock when older. 18.25 x 23.5 cm. (w/out mount); 26 x 33.5 cm. (w/mount).
  - Item 34: Unidentified man, probably officer of TWUA, black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Fabian Bachrach [photographer]. Gelatin silver print, 195-? Image depicts man in his late 50s or early 60s from chest up, wearing suit and tie, also wearing glasses. Probably an officer of the Textile Workers Union of America but identity is unknown. 20.25 x 25.25 cm. (w/out mount); 26 x 33.5 cm. (w/mount).
  - Item 40: John Chupka, general secretary-treasurer, TWUA., black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 1)